Thomas J. Taylor

web-application programmer

website: tomtaylor.name

Flat 3, Brick Lane High Street, Henfield BN5 9DB.

tel: (+44)7711084485 e-mail: hello@tomtaylor.name github: github/taylortom

About

Full-stack web developer with 5 years professional experience currently working full-time on a global open-source digital learning project, but always on the look-out for exciting new opportunities.

I am highly adaptable; my technical programming background is balanced with an eye for good design and an attention for detail. I also have an excellent work ethic, which comes from having a passion for what I do; I thrive on the challenge of using new technologies to develop engaging products that give users enjoyment in simply being used.

I have considerable experience in leadership roles, both in technical development teams, as well as cross-discipline product ownership, and pride myself on my ability to develop good respectful relationships with my team; a strong team bond has always been at the heart of my greatest successes.

Skills

Web development: HTML, CSS (& LESS), JS (ES6+, Node.js, Vue.js), NoSQL (MongoDB), TDD & automated testing (CasperJS, Mocha), CI (Travis).

Misc: Reqs. analysis, spec definition, software architecture, product ownership, project management, VCS (Git, Subversion), document preparation (IATEX).

Hobbies & Interests

User experience, digital learning, ethical software practices, open-source software, clean code(!) Black coffee, photography, Japan, Leicester City F.C. fitness, The Rebel Alliance.

Education

2008–2012 Bachelor of Science - University of Brighton, East Sussex.

Computer Science (Games) with first-class honours.

Major project: An experiment into using academic machine learning techniques in a game context. Developed in Objective-C for iOS4 using the Cocos2D game engine. Source code available at github.com/taylortom/cogito.

Modules studied: Concurrency and Client-Server Computing, Advanced AI, Computer Graphics Algorithms, Object-Oriented Software Design, Computer Systems Architecture, Mathematics, Human Computer Interaction, Requirements Analysis.

2006-2008 **A-level** - Wreake Valley Community College, Leicestershire.

> A2: Graphics with Materials Technology (A), English Literature (B), Biology (C) **AS**: Chemistry (C), General Studies (C).

GCSE - Wreake Valley Community College, Leicestershire. 2004 - 2006

> Mathematics (A), English Lit. (A), English Lang. (B), Double Science (AA), IT (A), Business Studies (A), Business & Communication Systems (A*), Graphic Products (A), Music (B), French (B), German (C), Humanities (A), R.E. (A).

Professional Experience

Nov 2014 – Present

Open-source Learning Technologies Developer - Kineo

Role as a lead developer on the Adapt project's Node.js-based authoring tool.

I take a lead on the product ownership of the authoring tool, which involves driving the roadmap and architecting new features/core changes, organising meetings, liaising with and managing contributors and the direct development of features and bug-fixes.

Community engagement is another major aspect to my role. I am involved in on-boarding and training both internal and external staff; organising, attending and presenting at community events; engaging the community directly to garner feedback and drive new feature development. This community aspect to my role is very important to me, as I get to have a unique relationship with our end users.

Personal accomplishments

- Formalised Adapt's development workflow (based on Agile & git flow elements). Involved documenting 'rules', and enforcing these with CI tools.
- Led Kineo's adoption of the Adapt authoring tool internally, which required considerable development work as well as knowledge-sharing.
- Led the re-architecture of the authoring tool, which involved identifying areas of weakness, proposing and documenting solutions, and implementing those solutions (directly and by managing working groups for individual areas).

I get much enjoyment out of working on the Adapt project, due in part to its ethical core principles, but also the satisfaction of working on a product that's both valued by its users and also forcing a change in the learning industry as a whole.

Jul 2012 – Oct 2014

Technical Consultant - Kineo

Junior TC: Jul 2012 – May 2013 Role as an ActionScript 2/3 and later JavaScript developer working on digital learning courses for many high-profile private and public sector clients.

Student Placement: Jul 2010 – Aug 2011 I was responsible for many client projects, from the requirements analysis and solution architecture to development and bug-fixing. I developed an ability to thrive under high pressure during this role due to our usually very short development cycles.

Personal accomplishments

• Architected and built a complex data-visualisation widget using HTML5 Canvas in an award-winning flagship project. A significant part of this task was the R&D and subsequent identification of appropriate technologies and tools.